<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Noetic Nought</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/</link><description>For an idle mind is the devil's workshop.</description><atom:link href="http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/rss.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 01:47:18 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Bookmarks [2014-11-01]</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/bookmarks-2014-11-01.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://thoughtcatalog.com/brianna-wiest/2013/04/50-ways-to-love-someone/"&gt;50 Ways To Love Someone | Thought Catalog&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Go for walks together as much as you’re able.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://research.microsoft.com/en-US/people/kannan/book-no-solutions-aug-21-2014.pdf"&gt;Foundations of Data Science&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
These notes are a first draft of a book being written by Hopcroft and Kannan
and in many places are incomplete. However, the notes are in good enough
shape to prepare lectures for a modern theoretical course in computer
science. Please do not put solutions to exercises online as it is important
for students to work out solutions for themselves rather than copy them from
the internet.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://asyncio.org/"&gt;Asyncio&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Curated content from around the net to get started with asyncio
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/s16h/py-must-watch"&gt;s16h/py-must-watch · GitHub&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Must-watch videos about Python.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/josephmisiti/awesome-machine-learning#python"&gt;josephmisiti/awesome-machine-learning · GitHub&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
A curated list of awesome machine learning frameworks, libraries and software
(by language).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.masteringemacs.org/about"&gt;About - Mastering Emacs&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The blog will cover all facets of Emacs and will be suitable for beginners
and – I hope – experts alike.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>bookmarks</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/bookmarks-2014-11-01.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2014 20:16:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Quotes [2014-11-01]</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/quotes-2014-11-01.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wanted to change the world. But I have found that the only thing
one can be sure of changing is oneself. ~ Aldous Huxley
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The true voyage of discovery consists not of going to new places,
but of having a new pair of eyes. — Marcel Proust (1871–1922)
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;All that is necessary for evil to triumph is for good men to do nothing. — Edmund Burke
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"I think that it's extraordinarily important that we in computer science keep
  fun in computing. When it started out, it was an awful lot of fun. Of course,
the paying customers got shafted every now and then, and after a while we
began to take their complaints seriously. We began to feel as if we really
were responsible for the successful, error-free perfect use of these
machines. I don't think we are. I think we're responsible for stretching
them, setting them off in new directions, and keeping fun in the house. I
hope the field of computer science never loses its sense of fun. Above all, I
hope we don't become missionaries. Don't feel as if you're Bible
salesmen. The world has too many of those already. What you know about
computing other people will learn. Don't feel as if the key to successful
computing is only in your hands. What's in your hands, I think and hope, is
intelligence: the ability to see the machine as more than when you were first
led up to it, that you can make it more." – &lt;i&gt;Alan J. Perlis (April 1,
1922-February 7, 1990)&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Forgetting is like radiation: you cannot smell it, you cannot taste it, and
  when you finally notice the damage, it is already irreversible – &lt;i&gt;Piotr
Wozniack&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;"Computer Science is no more about computers than astronomy is about telescopes" – &lt;i&gt;Edsger Dijkstra&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>quotes</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/quotes-2014-11-01.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2014 20:16:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Martin Fowler on Refactoring @ RubyRogues</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/martin-fowler-on-refactoring-rubyrogues.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I stumbled on a &lt;a href="http://rubyrogues.com/178-rr-book-club-refactoring-ruby-with-martin-fowler/"&gt;Ruby Rogues podcast&lt;/a&gt; yesterday, which had &lt;a href="http://martinfowlwer.com"&gt;Martin Fowler&lt;/a&gt; as the
guest.  I really enjoyed the discussion on Refactoring (the noun, the verb and
the book!)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Martin clarified in the podcast that refactoring (the verb/process) is a
sequence of very small refactorings, while you keep making sure that you can
run the test suite always.  A refactoring (noun) is a change where you change
the structure of the code without any externally observable changes, with the
intent of making it easier to understand and cheaper to change in future.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I also really liked the metaphor of a 'healthy code base'.  Refactoring is,
then, the process of keeping healthy – exercise, speaking metaphorically.  You
can stack up all the exercise you need to do, until you get really unfit.
Refactoring, similarly, needs to be done regularly, to keep the code base
healthy.  This lets you go faster, in the future.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I also really liked the advise about trying to push back the mental contexts
you build, while trying to debug/understand some code that is not very clear,
by refactoring the code to make it clearer.  Code needn't be one big chunk of
cryptographic text.  Code is writing.  It should be clear and understandable.
Or, at least we should strive to make it so!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The discussion, as always on this podcast, was very lively, pleasant and
enjoyable! Enjoy!
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>advice</category><category>code</category><category>programming</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/martin-fowler-on-refactoring-rubyrogues.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2014 14:23:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Learning about Spaced Repetition, SuperMemo, Org-drill, et al.</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/learning-about-spaced-repetition-supermemo-org-drill-et-al.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I have been reading a bunch of articles on the SuperMemo site (including the
&lt;a href="http://www.supermemo.com/english/ol.htm"&gt;original thesis&lt;/a&gt; of P. A. Wozniack, the creator of SuperMemo).  I initially
started off trying to understand the algorithms SM2,5 and 8 which org-drill
implements, but reading the articles has given me a lot of general background
and theory on how memory works, and why SuperMemo is as effective as it is (for
those who stick with it).  This blog post is an attempt to summarize and
capture what I have read in all those &lt;a href="http://www.supermemo.com/english/contents.htm"&gt;articles&lt;/a&gt;, and not get lost in them.  I
would recommend reading the thesis and the suggested reading there, yourself,
but if you really don't want to – this blog post + the summary in &lt;a href="http://www.supermemo.com/articles/20rules.htm#Prioritize"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a href="http://www.supermemo.com/articles/decalog.htm#decalog"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; would be a good alternative.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Memory works by repetition.  Each time you recall a fact, the time it takes
for the memory to fade increases.  Spaced repetition is the idea of repeating
items, just when you are about to forget them – trying to optimize the time
spent on learning, as well as the retention of learned material.
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Prioritization of the items we need to learn is key to being able to stick to
Spaced repetition.  Beginners tend to be over-enthusiastic about the
technique and fill up their system with stuff that they don't really care
about.  Applicability of the knowledge you are trying to gain, is a good test
for whether or not it goes into your system.
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Each version of SuperMemo comes with a slightly modified (on most occassions,
improved!) algorithm.  SM2, SM5, … refer to these algorithms. Org-drill
currently supports only sm2,5 and 8.  It may be worth looking at sm15/16 and
seeing if it can be implemented and is worth doing.  In any case, using any
of these is &lt;b&gt;way&lt;/b&gt; better than not using Spaced repetition at all.
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Understanding what we are trying to learn goes a long way in helping
memory. It is, therefore, good to start with basic material. People have been
surprised by how easily the advanced stuff fell into place, once they had the
basics covered.
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Keep items in the system simple.  Stick to the minimum information
principle.  Keeping it simple, doesn't mean you leave out on learning the
complex stuff; instead break it into simpler components.  Simpler items has
the following advantages:

&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple is easier to remember.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simpler items are easier to schedule.  You get more resolution to figure
out what the problem areas are.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple makes brings in redundancy automatically.  And &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Redundancy_is_good"&gt;redundancy is good&lt;/a&gt;
for memory, just like it is for managing hardware failure.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Keep learning fun!  Don't make review sessions a chore.  Think about the
material you are reviewing. Edit/delete/improve items based on your reviews,
then and there. Stay active.
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;It is useful to add a link to the source of the items added to your system,
considering that you wish to use the system over a long period of time
(ideally, the rest of your life!)
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Prioritize, add examples, appeal to your emotional state, link to existing
knowledge, use images. Anything else that works for you!  Use all of these
techniques, that work well and you probably already use in everyday life, in
the items you add to your system, to make them easier to recall.
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Being physically fit and healthy is important for being so
mentally. Exercise, sleep, eat well, avoid caffeine.
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Try &lt;a href="http://www.supermemo.com/help/read.htm"&gt;incremental&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.supermemo.com/articles/devour.htm"&gt;reading&lt;/a&gt;, as an input source of items into your memory system.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>learning</category><category>life</category><category>memory</category><category>software</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/learning-about-spaced-repetition-supermemo-org-drill-et-al.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2014 13:37:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Simple org-clock and gnome/pidgin integration</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/simple-org-clock-and-gnomepidgin-integration.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I have been trying to get back to using org-mode and its clocking
functionality, more often than not.  I used to use it a lot, a few years ago,
and haven't been using it, since I had been in my last job.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
To help with it, I decided to integrate clocking in and out with changing
status on Pidgin, and turning notifications on and off in Gnome.  Here's a few
lines of code that does this for me.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;defadvice&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;org&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;clock&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;after&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;pc&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;org&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;clock&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;optional&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;select&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;start&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;time&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="s"&gt;"Turn gnome notifications off."&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;dbus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;send&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;signal&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;session&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="s"&gt;"org.gnome.SessionManager"&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="s"&gt;"/org/gnome/SessionManager/Presence"&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="s"&gt;"org.gnome.SessionManager.Presence"&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="s"&gt;"SetStatus"&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;shell&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;command&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;"purple-remote setstatus?status=unavailable"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;defadvice&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;org&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;clock&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;out&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;after&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;pc&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;org&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;clock&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;out&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;optional&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;switch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;state&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;fail&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;quietly&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;at&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;time&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="s"&gt;"Turn gnome notifications back on."&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;dbus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;send&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;signal&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;session&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="s"&gt;"org.gnome.SessionManager"&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="s"&gt;"/org/gnome/SessionManager/Presence"&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="s"&gt;"org.gnome.SessionManager.Presence"&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="s"&gt;"SetStatus"&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;shell&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;command&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;"purple-remote setstatus?status=available"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>code</category><category>elisp</category><category>orgmode</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/simple-org-clock-and-gnomepidgin-integration.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2014 20:43:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Making PyCon India better (for myself)</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/making-pycon-india-better-for-myself.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I've &lt;a href="http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/notes-from-pycon.html"&gt;ranted before&lt;/a&gt; about PyCon not meeting my expectations, and I even skipped
going to the last PyCon.  Somehow, I hoped that it would be better this year,
but no such thing happened.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I should strictly not attend any talks, at the next conference I am at.  Even
if the topic seems interesting, I should refrain from attending any talks,
unless I know that a speaker is entertaining.
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I should be going there to meet old friends, meet a few new people, and
mostly hacking on my stuff.  May be aim to show something at the lightning
talks at the end of second day, based on what I did during the rest of the
event.
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Participate more actively in open spaces, and may be initiate or suggest some
myself.  Sprints for bug fixing, adding new features to a project may be a
good way to get new developers to start contributing to FOSS projects.  It
would be even better to be in touch with folks before the event, and use this
opportunity to iron out kinks.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I think the talks could be improved drastically. A lot&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id="fnr.1" name="fnr.1" class="footref" href="http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/making-pycon-india-better-for-myself.html#fn.1"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;, &lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id="fnr.2" name="fnr.2" class="footref" href="http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/making-pycon-india-better-for-myself.html#fn.2"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; has been said,
already.  Here's a summary of how I see it.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beginner/Novice talks doesn't mean bad talks.  A talk with a good narrative,
that drives home a point, that may be familiar to most of the audience, would
still make a good talk.  I don't mind reading a good blog post/book on a
topic I already know, because there is joy in reading/listening to "good"
stuff.
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Talks cannot be judged by titles or an abstract.  Taking inspiration from
PyCon US, we could

&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask for a video recording of a previous talk or a short home-made
recording of the speaker presenting some topic.
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Ask for a granular outline &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id="fnr.3" name="fnr.3" class="footref" href="http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/making-pycon-india-better-for-myself.html#fn.3"&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; along with rough timing information, instead of
just an abstract.
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Have a bunch of resources &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id="fnr.4" name="fnr.4" class="footref" href="http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/making-pycon-india-better-for-myself.html#fn.4"&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;, &lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id="fnr.5" name="fnr.5" class="footref" href="http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/making-pycon-india-better-for-myself.html#fn.5"&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;, &lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id="fnr.6" name="fnr.6" class="footref" href="http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/making-pycon-india-better-for-myself.html#fn.6"&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; available for speakers to improve on their
proposals/accepted talks.
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Have a bunch of 20 or 30 minute talks, and very few longer (45 min) talk
slots.
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Encourage speakers to try connecting their laptops and iron out
"presentation" kinks on the day before their talks/lunch/other allotted
times. Technical issues like fonts being too small, mics not working,
adjusting the volume/other settings for the speaker, etc. can and should be
fixed before hand.
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The talk review committee could also take notes from attending some of the
talks, and compare it against their notes when they accepted the talk, to
improve the talk selection process.  Some of it could be valuable feedback
for the speakers too.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id="footnotes"&gt;
&lt;h2 class="footnotes"&gt;Footnotes: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="text-footnotes"&gt;

&lt;div class="footdef"&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id="fn.1" name="fn.1" class="footnum" href="http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/making-pycon-india-better-for-myself.html#fnr.1"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;p class="footpara"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/+sankarshanmukhopadhyay/posts/8QY4o3hiyLT"&gt;https://plus.google.com/+sankarshanmukhopadhyay/posts/8QY4o3hiyLT&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="footdef"&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id="fn.2" name="fn.2" class="footnum" href="http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/making-pycon-india-better-for-myself.html#fnr.2"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;p class="footpara"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://mail.python.org/pipermail/inpycon/2014-October/009189.html"&gt;https://mail.python.org/pipermail/inpycon/2014-October/009189.html&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="footdef"&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id="fn.3" name="fn.3" class="footnum" href="http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/making-pycon-india-better-for-myself.html#fnr.3"&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;p class="footpara"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://us.pycon.org/2015/speaking/proposal_advice/samples/SpacePug/"&gt;https://us.pycon.org/2015/speaking/proposal_advice/samples/SpacePug/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="footdef"&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id="fn.4" name="fn.4" class="footnum" href="http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/making-pycon-india-better-for-myself.html#fnr.4"&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;p class="footpara"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://us.pycon.org/2015/speaking/proposal-resources/"&gt;https://us.pycon.org/2015/speaking/proposal-resources/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="footdef"&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id="fn.5" name="fn.5" class="footnum" href="http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/making-pycon-india-better-for-myself.html#fnr.5"&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;p class="footpara"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://doughellmann.com/2011/10/18/how-i-review-a-pycon-talk-proposal.html"&gt;http://doughellmann.com/2011/10/18/how-i-review-a-pycon-talk-proposal.html&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="footdef"&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id="fn.6" name="fn.6" class="footnum" href="http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/making-pycon-india-better-for-myself.html#fnr.6"&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;p class="footpara"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.craigkerstiens.com/2012/06/19/pro-tips-for-conference-talks/"&gt;http://www.craigkerstiens.com/2012/06/19/pro-tips-for-conference-talks/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>event</category><category>pycon</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/making-pycon-india-better-for-myself.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 11:53:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Learning to use Org-drill</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/learning-to-use-org-drill.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Org-drill is an Org-mode extension that provides spaced-repetition and
flash-card functionality.  It has a &lt;a href="http://orgmode.org/worg/org-contrib/org-drill.html"&gt;wonderful documentation on Worg&lt;/a&gt;, but
somehow I couldn't get myself to read the whole document, and setup org-drill,
until now.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The setup is quite straight forward, once you have org-mode along with the
&lt;code&gt;contrib&lt;/code&gt; packages.  Just &lt;code&gt;(require 'org-drill)&lt;/code&gt;, and you are all set!  To add
a new card, all you need to do is add a &lt;code&gt;:drill:&lt;/code&gt; tag to the items you wish to
"Org-drill".  You can start a review session with simply &lt;code&gt;M-x org-drill&lt;/code&gt;.  You
will be shown flash cards, and you can rate how correct and comfortable you
were, in answering the questions.  Based on your responses, the cards are
scheduled for review.  Start another review session, whenever you need one!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
What I could only understand once I got myself to read the whole document was
that:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The default scope of a drill session is the current file.  But, you can start
sessions with scopes like current tree, current directory, or a specified
list of files. This is super-useful!
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The review sessions are not automatically scheduled, based on when you
schedule failed flash-cards.  Scheduling the review for a card only sets a
due-date for them, and effects, what you are asked in your next session.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Cram mode and incremental reading are also things I want to try, as I go along.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Happy Learning!
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>learning</category><category>orgmode</category><category>software</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/learning-to-use-org-drill.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 04:07:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bookmarks [2014-10-10]</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/bookmarks-2014-10-10.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://graydon.livejournal.com/186550.html"&gt;frog hop - technicalities: "not rocket science" (the story of monotone and bors)&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The Not Rocket Science Rule Of Software Engineering: automatically maintain a
repository of code that always passes all the tests
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/BwIsAVMIUAEReH3.jpg"&gt;Intellectual conversations - Image (500×700)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://firstround.com/article/What-to-Do-at-the-Crossroads-of-Should-and-Must"&gt;When You're at the Crossroads of Should and Must&lt;/a&gt;
  This is a story about two roads — Should and Must. It’s a pep talk for anyone
who’s chosen Should far too long — months, years, maybe a lifetime, and feels
like it’s about time they give Must a shot.
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://rampantgames.com/blog/?p=7745"&gt;Black Triangles&lt;/a&gt;
  And when progress seems a little slow because you are doing a bunch of
hardcore architecture work, just remember it’s a black triangle.
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://alyssafrazee.com/unstructured-time.html"&gt;motivation and unstructured time: successes and failures - alyssa frazee&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
some of the tactics I've tried to get myself into "working mode."
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>bookmarks</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/bookmarks-2014-10-10.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 09:24:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hacker School, 2014-08-28</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/hacker-school-2014-08-28.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
All good things must come to an end, and so did our batch!  We got our Hacker
School t-shirts, and had a super fun picnic at Prospect Park.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>hackerschool</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/hacker-school-2014-08-28.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2014 16:24:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hacker School, 2014-08-27</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/hacker-school-2014-08-27.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I spent the whole of yesterday just working on the LED-bot.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spent some time cleaning up meta-stuff about the project, making it a real
package, adding a setup.py, added LICENSE &amp;amp; AUTHOR files, etc.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I found it really frustrating that there's no good/standard way to remove
duplication of information between pip's &lt;code&gt;requirements.txt&lt;/code&gt; and
&lt;code&gt;install_requires&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We got the bot running on the Beagle Bone, but it turned out to be too slow.
After some playing around with trying to get rid of Python for-loops, I was
able to use PIL's &lt;code&gt;image.tobytes&lt;/code&gt; and some image cropping to get the data to
be sent to the LEDs, and it sped up the display quite a bit.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>PIL</category><category>hackerschool</category><category>python</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/hacker-school-2014-08-27.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2014 13:51:30 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>