<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Noetic Nought (bookmarks)</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/</link><description></description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2014 12:54:20 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Bookmarks [2014-08-15]</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/bookmarks-2014-08-15.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.gigamonkeys.com/code-reading/"&gt;Code is not literature&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The ideal presentation should be aimed at an audience of gentleman
and lady programmers—smart, and generally capable but without,
necessarily, any specific knowledge of the domain from which the
code comes. Presentations should provide enough context for the
audience to to understand what the code is and should explain any
details of the implementation language that may be obscure to the
average programmer.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://jenkins-ci.org/content/summary-report-git-repository-disruption-incident-nov-10th"&gt;Summary Report: Git Repository Disruption Incident of Nov 10th | Jenkins CI&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
As reported in various places, there was an incident in early
November where commits in our Git repositories have become misplaced
temporarily by accident. By the mid next week we were able to
resurrect all the commits and things are back to normal now.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
As there are many confusions and misunderstandings in people’s
commentary, we wrote this post to clarify what exactly happened and
what we are doing to prevent this.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://old.lwn.net/2000/0824/a/esr-sharing.php3"&gt;a/esr-sharing&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I used to worry about what would happen if Linus got hit by a truck.
With all respect, I still worry about what will happen if the
complexity of the kernel exceeds the scope of your astonishing
native talent before you grow up.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://learn.adafruit.com/adafruits-raspberry-pi-lesson-5-using-a-console-cable/overview"&gt;Overview | Adafruit's Raspberry Pi Lesson 5. Using a Console Cable | Adafruit Learning System&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In this lesson you will learn how to remote control your Raspberry Pi with a
console cable.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.vice.com/read/a-german-guy-wants-to-give-you-a-bunch-of-money-for-nothing"&gt;A German Guy Wants to Give You a Bunch of Money for Nothing | VICE United States&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
After he stopped working earlier this year to live off the $1,300 he makes
from his startup each month, Bohmeyer says his life has radically changed. So
he started “My Basic Income”, a new initiative looking to raise enough money
to pay someone $1,300 a month for a year, no strings attached.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>bookmarks</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/bookmarks-2014-08-15.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2014 02:07:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bookmarks [2014-06-10]</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/bookmarks-2014-06-10.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://marss86.org/~marss86/index.php/Home"&gt;Marss86&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
MARSSx86 (MARSS for short) is a tool for cycle accurate full system
simulation of the x86-64 architecture, specifically multicore
implementations. Our goal is to create a simple yet efficient full
system architectural simulation environment based on existing tools.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/p/b9b1b173f4eb"&gt;What 50 pounds of clay can teach you about design — Medium&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
while the “quantity” group was busily churning out piles of work”and
learning from their mistakes”the “quality” group had sat theorizing
about perfection, and in the end had little more to show for their
efforts than grandiose theories and a pile of dead clay.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.metaobject.com/2014/05/why-i-don-mock.html"&gt;metablog: Why I don't mock&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
So don't mock. Because it's impolite to not listen to what your code
is trying to tell you.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://opensource.com/life/14/5/true-value-of-open-source"&gt;Where's the value in open source? | Opensource.com&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Open source is about the people involved. Code can be replaced,
re-written, even removed completely, and the project will continue
to move forward. The open source community is made up of people who
have dedicated their time and their life to see its success.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.vex.net/~trebla/haskell/learn-sources.xhtml"&gt;I Recommend These for Learning Haskell&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
A friend of mine recommends reading 3 calculus books to learn
calculus. I generalize it to reading from 3 sources to learn
anything. I also postulate a law: the 3rd source you read is the
best.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>bookmarks</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/bookmarks-2014-06-10.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2014 13:47:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bookmarks [2014-05-19]</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/bookmarks-2014-05-19.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://sivers.org/ml"&gt;The Meaning of Life | Derek Sivers&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Socrates said the unexamined life is not worth living. What about
the forgotten life?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.samaltman.com/advice-for-ambitious-19-year-olds"&gt;Advice for ambitious 19 year olds - Sam Altman&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The best people always seem to be building stuff and hanging around
smart people, so if you have to decide between several options, this
may be a good filter.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://canadianultimate.com/index.php/about-uc/1/16"&gt;Resources&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
There are many coaching resources available for coaches and players
to help develop Ultimate programs and improve skills.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.discnw.org/youth/coaches.html"&gt;Coaches&lt;/a&gt;
  Here is a list of resources for coaches and, of course, team
captains, players, PE teachers, or anyone else who wants to teach
skills, find a team to coach, or learn drills, plays, and
strategy.
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://thoughtcatalog.com/lance-pauker/2014/05/15-people-on-the-one-book-you-should-read-this-summer/"&gt;17 People On The One Book You Should Definitely Read This Summer | Thought Catalog&lt;/a&gt;
  I figured I’d ask some young #tastemakers to share their suggestions
with the world.

&lt;p&gt;
The list below is rather diverse in style — from comedy, to
business, to self-help, to fantasy, to classic literature-y books
that you could smartly reference at “functions,” there might just be
something for everyone.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>bookmarks</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/bookmarks-2014-05-19.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 06:30:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bookmarks [2014-05-04]</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/bookmarks-2014-05-04.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://mauveweb.co.uk/posts/2014/04/learning-rust.html"&gt;Learning Rust | Mauveweb&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I also spent some time working out how to call Rust code from
Python, which would allow me to use both languages to their strength
in the same project.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://yaledailynews.com/crosscampus/2012/05/27/keegan-the-opposite-of-loneliness/"&gt;KEEGAN: The Opposite of Loneliness | Cross Campus&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The notion that it’s too late to do anything is comical. It’s
hilarious. We’re graduating college. We’re so young. We can’t, we
MUST not lose this sense of possibility because in the end, it’s all
we have.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
We don’t have a word for the opposite of loneliness, but if we did,
I’d say that’s how I feel at Yale. How I feel right now. Here. With
all of you. In love, impressed, humbled, scared. And we don’t have
to lose that.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
We’re in this together, 2012. Let’s make something happen to this
world.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://skydmagazine.com/2012/01/raise-your-game-day-1/"&gt;Raise Your Game: Day 1 - Skyd Magazine&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This article is Part 1 in a 5 part series from Ben Wiggins on
succeeding in the sport of Ultimate.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://qnrq.se/why-i-wont-work-for-google/"&gt;Why I won’t work for Google | qnrq&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
“Gentlemen do not read each other’s mail.” – Henry L. Stimson
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.umbrelr.com/young-mother-giving-kids-dont-blame-her/"&gt;This Young Mother Is Giving Up On Her Kids And I Don't Blame Her.&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
My kids are not the center of my world because I love them enough
not to allow them to be.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>bookmarks</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/bookmarks-2014-05-04.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 10:30:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bookmarks [2014-04-29]</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/bookmarks-2014-04-29.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://ejohn.org/blog/write-code-every-day/"&gt;John Resig - Write Code Every Day&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Inspired by the incredible work that Jennifer Dewalt completed last
year, in which she taught herself programming by building 180 web
sites in 180 days, I felt compelled to try a similar tactic: working
on my side projects every single day.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://jvns.ca/blog/2014/04/20/debug-your-programs-like-theyre-closed-source/"&gt;Debug your programs like they're closed source! - Julia Evans&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
My favorite way to learn more, honestly, is to just strace random
programs and see what I find out. It’s a great way to spend a rainy
Sunday afternoon! =)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://lorenabarba.com/blog/announcing-aeropython/"&gt;Announcing AeroPython! - Lorena A. Barba Group&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
We now announce the public release of the 11 lessons that make
   AeroPython! Find them on the public GitHub repository.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.drdobbs.com/architecture-and-design/how-i-came-to-write-d/240165322"&gt;How I Came to Write D | Dr Dobb's&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Nobody could possibly work on compilers for 15+ years and not come
up with ideas for language improvements. I tried out many language
improvements in the C and C++ compilers, and they all fell flat.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.harrywolff.com/dont-deal-with-it-fix-it/"&gt;Don't Deal With It, Fix It&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I've learned that I have the power to fix things around me that I
don't like. I don't need to just deal with it because that's just
the way things are. I have the power to shape the world around
me. It's just a matter of believing that I can change things. Just
believing is all I need to actually take the first step towards
taking action.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.tjll.net/ssh-kung-fu/"&gt;Tyblog | SSH Kung Fu&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
What follows is a list for some of my use cases that leverage the
power of ssh.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>bookmarks</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/bookmarks-2014-04-29.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2014 22:30:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bookmarks [2014-04-11]</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/bookmarks-2014-04-11.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://maryrosecook.com/blog/post/new-york-2014"&gt;New York, 2014 at Mary Rose Cook&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
A video I made about Hacker School.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://maryrosecook.com/blog/post/hacker-school-testimonial"&gt;Hacker School testimonial at Mary Rose Cook&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The hours at Hacker School feel precious. This is the fastest period
of learning in my life. I’m coming back.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://tech.dropbox.com/2014/04/introducing-pyston-an-upcoming-jit-based-python-implementation/"&gt;Dropbox Tech Blog » Blog Archive » Introducing Pyston: an upcoming, JIT-based Python implementation&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The goal of the project is to produce a high-performance Python
implementation that can push Python into domains dominated by
traditional systems languages like C++.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.gabrielweinberg.com/blog/2011/01/on-not-hiring.html"&gt;On not hiring&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Hiring is hard. Not hiring can seem even harder, but often isn't.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>bookmarks</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/bookmarks-2014-04-11.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2014 06:30:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bookmarks [2014-03-23]</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/bookmarks-2014-03-23.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://mathamy.com/import-accio-bootstrapping-python-grammar.html"&gt;Replacing `import` with `accio`: A Dive into Bootstrapping and Python's Grammar&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
At Hacker School, I've been building an alternate universe Python by
overwriting builtin functions and statements with Harry Potter
spells.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://nautil.us/issue/11/light/falling-in-love-with-the-dark"&gt;Falling in Love With the Dark - Issue 11: Light - Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
“The first time people come out for dark skies, and we get Bortle
Class 1 and 2 here, it affects them deeply,” Carroll said. “They’re
blown away. The connection with the stars is inside all of us, but
it has been sequestered away.”
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.jayway.com/2013/03/03/git-is-a-purely-functional-data-structure/"&gt;Git is a purely functional data structure – Jayway&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Git can be accurately understood as a fairly simple functional data
structure. Instead of explaining Git in terms version control, we
can see the ability to do version control as an emergent property of
using that data structure. I think talking about Git in this manner
will more accurately convey the simplicity and power of Git better
than any comparisons with centralized version control systems can
accomplish.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://tech.blog.aknin.name/2010/04/02/pythons-innards-introduction/"&gt;Python’s Innards: Introduction | NIL: .to write(1) ~ help:about&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This post marks the beginning of what should develop to a series on
Python’s internals, I’m writing it since I believe that explaining
something is the best way to grok it, and I’d very much like to be
able to visualize more of Python’s ‘funky green gibberish soup’ as I
read Python code.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://jvns.ca/blog/2014/03/21/my-rust-os-will-never-be-finished/"&gt;My Rust OS will never be finished (and it's a success!) - Julia Evans&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Not finishing your project doesn’t mean it’s not a success. It
depends what your goals are the for the project! I wrote an
operating system in Rust to learn, and I learned a ton. It’s not
finished, and it won’t be.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>bookmarks</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/bookmarks-2014-03-23.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 17:18:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bookmarks [2014-03-12]</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/bookmarks-2014-03-12.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.mehdi-khalili.com/never-judge-a-programmer-by-their-commit-history#.UwiURItePPo.hackernews"&gt;Never judge a programmer by their commit history - Mehdi Khalili&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Here is a few things I have either experienced personally or seen
happen to great developers that led to bad code
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.otexts.org/book/sfml"&gt;Statistical foundations of machine learning | OTexts&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
We are in the era of big data. The procedure for finding useful
patterns in data is known by different names in different
communities but more and more, it is grouped under the label of
machine learning. This handbook aims to present the statistical
foundations of machine learning intended as the discipline which
deals with the automatic design of models from data.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.gleitzman.com/post/43330157197/howdoi-instant-coding-answers-via-the-command-line"&gt;Howdoi – Instant Coding Answers via the Command Line - Benjamin Gleitzman's Blog&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
One of my favorite collaborations to come out of the illustrious
Oxidized Bismuth Blogger (OxBiz) ideation list is howdoi, a tool for
instant coding answers via the command line.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://lemire.me/blog/archives/2014/03/10/elegance-as-a-luxury/"&gt;Elegance as a luxury&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
But once you see your brain as a CPU, then a more practical question
arises. How do you organize the problems to maximize the efficiency
of your brain…
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.bayareadisc.org/2013/10/30/what-ultimate-does-for-daughters/"&gt;What Ultimate Does for Daughters | Bay Area Disc Association&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In each case, it’s assumed that they are all the same kind of people
— Ultimate people. These kind of people are family of a kind forged
by lots of work, lots of experience and more fun than seems quite
reasonable.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://jvns.ca/blog/2014/03/10/help/"&gt;Hacker School's Secret Strategy for Being Super Productive (or: Help.) - Julia Evans&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
What if everybody asked questions when they needed help? What if
helping people was everyone’s default procrastination method?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>bookmarks</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/bookmarks-2014-03-12.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 16:49:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bookmarks [2014-02-21]</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/bookmarks-2014-02-21.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/ramonasuciu/ghostdriver_tests"&gt;ramonasuciu/ghostdriver&lt;sub&gt;tests&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Basic tests with PhantomJS &amp;amp; GhostDriver
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://wikichen.is/writing/live-slowly/"&gt;Live Slowly | wikichen&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In an afternoon, she taught me how to live slowly, to live better.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://blogs.ch.cam.ac.uk/pmr/2014/02/18/machines-are-better-referees-than-humans-but-well-be-sued-if-we-use-them/"&gt;Machines are better referees than humans but we’ll be sued if we use them « petermr's blog&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
And the scientific literature will continue to be stuffed full of
errors. And people will continue to die because of them.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Does anyone care? I don’t think so as no-one (ZERO) from a
University has commented on my analysis of Elsevier’s restrictive
TDM licence. They’ll just go ahead and sign it. Because it’s the
easiest thing to do.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.boredpanda.com/must-see-historic-moments/"&gt;40 Must-See Photos From The Past | Bored Panda&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Perhaps the wars, poverty, fights for freedom and little miracles of
the past have lessons for us that we can use today?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hackerschool.com/blog/"&gt;Blog - Hacker School&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Hopefully I've convinced you that gdb a neat exploratory environment
for learning C. You can print the evaluation of expressions, examine
raw bytes in memory, and tinker with the type system using ptype.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>bookmarks</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/bookmarks-2014-02-21.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2014 02:22:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bookmarks [2014-02-12]</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/bookmarks-2014-02-12.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://shkspr.mobi/blog/2014/02/learning-to-code-vs-learning-computer-science/"&gt;Learning to Code vs Learning Computer Science ← Terence Eden's Blog&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Learning to code is merely teaching people to spell.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Computer Science is about what makes a poem beautiful, why
alliteration is alluring, how iambic pentameter unlocks the secrets
of Shakespeare.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.jeffknupp.com/blog/2014/01/28/need-a-project-idea-scratch-your-own-itch/"&gt;Need a Project Idea? Scratch Your Own Itch&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
how do you determine a need that isn't being fulfilled and might be
the basis for a project/business? Two ways. You could ask people
what problems they have that you might be able to help solve, or
(for introverts like me) examine what processes or services feel
needlessly difficult in your own life.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.ted.com/2013/06/20/generating-a-sculpture-from-a-hair-the-work-of-heather-dewey-hagborg/"&gt;Generating a portrait from a hair: The work of Heather Dewey-Hagborg | TED Blog&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Dewey-Hagborg’s work is super interesting, not to mention searingly
contemporary. “It’s a very accessible way for the public to engage
with this new technology. It really brings to light how powerful it
is, the idea that a hair from your head can fall on your street and
a perfect stranger can pick it up and know something about it,” she
says, adding: “With DNA sequencing becoming faster and cheaper, this
is the world we’re all going to be living in.”
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.paperplanes.de/2014/2/10/standing-desk.html"&gt;paperplanes. A Standing Desk Love Affair&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Standing up all day can be tough at first, but I'm much happier
working like that. Plus, when you finally switch off at night,
you'll feel like you've done more than just think and type.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://ouseful.open.ac.uk/blogarchive/014885.html"&gt;OUseful Info: The Cost of Meetings - How Much Return on Investment Do YOU Get?&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
If the counter is displayed during the meeting, then everyone can
decide whether or not the meeting is generating a sensible
return. Whoever has the courage to call off a meeting on the grounds
it probably isn't worth it should get 10% of the expected meeting
costs saved to spend on a project of their choice (no meetings
allowed ;-).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.braegger.pw/5-ways-to-burn-out-programming/"&gt;5 Ways To Burn Out Programming&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In short, it's easy to burnout. Do these 5 things, and you can
burnout too.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>bookmarks</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/bookmarks-2014-02-12.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 01:02:46 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>