<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Noetic Nought (debugging)</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/tags/debugging.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2015 17:21:16 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>WiFi Channels &amp; my router's random invisibility</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/wifi-channels-my-routers-random-invisibility.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
To update some data plan changes, I had to restart my router today.  I did so
from the (web) admin interface, from my dad's laptop. Guess what!  The router
goes invisible (to the laptop), after the restart!  Other devices were still
happily connected.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
There were a few occasions in the past when this laptop had failed to find our
home router.  The solution that worked for my dad before was to restart the
router; once, or may be a couple of times.  But, this time it didn't work.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I had a feeling this was something to do with "Channels", but I had no idea
what was going on.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I logged onto the router and started looking at the Wireless settings in the
hope of finding some clue, and there it was! &lt;code&gt;Wireless Channel: Auto Scan&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/images/auto-scan.jpg" alt="auto-scan.jpg"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
It was anybody's guess that some channels that the router uses weren't
supported by my dad's laptop.  The restarts &lt;b&gt;sometimes&lt;/b&gt; helped because the
router would scan for channels that it thinks would work well, and end-up using
something that the laptop's wifi card supported.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The router only had options of channels from 1 to 13.  To see what channels a
wifi card supports, you can run the &lt;code&gt;iwlist freq&lt;/code&gt; command.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;iwlist freq
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;eth1      26 channels in total; available frequencies :
	  Channel 01 : 2.412 GHz
	  Channel 02 : 2.417 GHz
	  Channel 03 : 2.422 GHz
	  Channel 04 : 2.427 GHz
	  Channel 05 : 2.432 GHz
	  Channel 06 : 2.437 GHz
	  Channel 07 : 2.442 GHz
	  Channel 08 : 2.447 GHz
	  Channel 09 : 2.452 GHz
	  Channel 10 : 2.457 GHz
	  Channel 11 : 2.462 GHz
	  Channel 12 : 2.467 GHz
	  Channel 13 : 2.472 GHz
	  Channel 14 : 2.484 GHz
	  Channel 36 : 5.18 GHz
	  Channel 38 : 5.19 GHz
	  Channel 40 : 5.2 GHz
	  Channel 42 : 5.21 GHz
	  Channel 44 : 5.22 GHz
	  Channel 46 : 5.23 GHz
	  Channel 48 : 5.24 GHz
	  Channel 149 : 5.745 GHz
	  Channel 153 : 5.765 GHz
	  Channel 157 : 5.785 GHz
	  Channel 161 : 5.805 GHz
	  Channel 165 : 5.825 GHz
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
So, the laptop's wifi card support all the channels that the router could use.
&lt;code&gt;iwlist freq&lt;/code&gt; also gives the current Channel if the device is already connected
to a router.  I ran this on my laptop and found that the router was using
&lt;code&gt;Channel 13&lt;/code&gt;.  Why the hell wouldn't this work?!  I don't know!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I decided to set a channel manually, but how do I pick a channel?  The idea of
"Auto Scan" is to find a channel that has relatively low interference.  How do
we do this manually?  &lt;code&gt;sudo iwlist scan&lt;/code&gt; scans for all the WiFi access points
nearby and gives detailed information about them, which includes the Channel.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
It looked like most of the routers nearby used channels 1 and 6, with a few 3s
and 4s.  Assuming, most of the other routers aren't doing this "Auto Scan"
business, I set my router to always use Channel 9, and the laptop seems to be
happily connected, now!
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>blag</category><category>debugging</category><category>hardware</category><category>howto</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/wifi-channels-my-routers-random-invisibility.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 06:18:50 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>