<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Noetic Nought (django)</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/</link><description></description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 00:08:55 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Hacker School, 2014-08-11</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/hacker-school-2014-08-11.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I spent about an hour in the morning testing out the staging blaggregator
instance, and things seemed to work as expected.  Side note, I got added as a
collaborator on the blaggregator repo!
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We worked through the first chapter on getting video working, but we mostly
ended up just copying code rather than actually understanding/carefully
studying it.  I'm not sure how I feel about it, but we got to display fancy
stuff.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wasn't feeling like working on any of my 'old'/'ongoing' projects, and
since Mondays don't feel very productive, I worked on writing a couple of
simple scripts to create twitter lists of HSers, batch wise.

&lt;p&gt;
For the HS API, I just reused some old code I had lying around from my
experiments with the OAuth2 API, though I had to tweak it a little bit to be
able to actually login, using requests. Something about CSRF tokens seems to
have changed.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In the process, I found that twitter's API isn't very pleasant to use.  Or
may be it's the fact that I was using python twitter client without getting
my own client id/key, but the whole experience of dealing with the twitter
API wasn't a pleasant one at all!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amber, Daria and I also spent about an hour white-boarding some problems from
the Cracking the Code Interview book.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I ended up fixing some minor issues with blaggregator and am hoping that the
long pending PR will be merged today.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>django</category><category>hackerschool</category><category>python</category><category>twitter</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/hacker-school-2014-08-11.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2014 15:16:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hacker School, 2014-07-03</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/hacker-school-2014-07-03.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I got distracted trying to add a hack to Hacker School's &lt;a href="https://github.com/sursh/blaggregator"&gt;blaggregator&lt;/a&gt;, to
enable posting to different channels on zulip.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I learnt a few things about Django.  Commented out references to views that
don't exists breaks templating.  Formsets didn't seem very convenient to use,
for editing data showing the user only partial forms.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I played around with Clang for a bit, to try and use libclang to parse the C
code for inspection, instead of writing one myself.  It sometimes feels like
an overkill, but it feels like it'll make the whole code more robust.  I'm
not sure.  I'll need to play around for a bit more to decide.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also finally got around to fix the resolution of my tty shells.  I was in a
bus, and wanted my laptop's battery to last longer, and decided to use a tty
shell with just emacs running. But, the resolution sucked.  So, I
fixed. Essentially it involved removing a blacklist file that an old version
of Nvidia drivers left behind in
&lt;code&gt;/usr/share/grub-gfxpayload-lists/blacklist/&lt;/code&gt; and setting
&lt;code&gt;GRUB_GFXMODE=1920x1080&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;/etc/default/grub&lt;/code&gt;.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Later in the evening I also bought the domain &lt;code&gt;octo.cat&lt;/code&gt;, given there were a
bunch of people buying cat domains, and talking about it on Zulip!
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Update [7/7/14]: I forgot to write about the presentations.  There were
interesting presentations!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/ambimorph/protagonist"&gt;Protagonist&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/pirate/mesh-networking"&gt;mesh networking&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://writing.brianruslim.com/2014/06/30/the-execution-context/"&gt;The Execution Context&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/stijlist/toolmaker/"&gt;toolmaker&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.ontoillogical.com/blog/2014/07/03/doorbot-overflow/"&gt;Building a better doorbot&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/buybackoff/Fredis"&gt;Fredis&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>django</category><category>hackerschool</category><category>python</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/hacker-school-2014-07-03.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2014 13:49:37 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>