<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Noetic Nought (fft)</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/</link><description></description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2014 18:07:41 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Hacker School, 2014-06-26</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/hacker-school-2014-06-26.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I played around a little bit with my &lt;code&gt;emacs&lt;/code&gt; configuration and got &lt;code&gt;jedi&lt;/code&gt;
working, with virtualenvs, thanks to &lt;code&gt;virtualenvwrapper.el&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continue to work on the singal processing stuff and built a DTMF decoder
using FFTs.  It's able to decode audacity generated audio, but not recorded
ones. I'm not sure what I'm doing wrong, yet.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As with every Thursday, there were a bunch of interesting presentations:
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A rice cooker hooked up to an arduino in an afternoon!
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A presentation on how scopes act as monoids
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An implementation of &lt;a href="http://people.csail.mit.edu/mrub/vidmag/"&gt;Eularian Video Magnification&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A regex engine visualizer using NetworkX.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;a href="https://github.com/ambimorph/protagonist"&gt;tag system to organize your files&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A web-socket based chat client
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Go Parser written in Go
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;…
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>dtmf</category><category>fft</category><category>hackerschool</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/hacker-school-2014-06-26.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2014 13:30:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hacker School, 2014-06-25</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/hacker-school-2014-06-25.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I like how some of the people here are taking check-ins so seriously.  A
bunch of people posted messages on Zulip, informing that they would not be
able to make it to check-ins, and seemed quite sorry about it.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check-ins are indeed useful.  At the end of every day, I review my work
wondering what I did, and sometimes end up pushing myself harder, to have
something reasonable to talk about during the check-ins!
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yesterday, I read up about FFTs and ended up playing around with &lt;code&gt;fft&lt;/code&gt; in
  &lt;code&gt;scipy&lt;/code&gt;, and played around with audacity, etc.  Nothing concrete, really.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There was a "goals" workshop by Stacey, where she talked about how to get the
most out of this batch of Hacker School, and then we split into groups of 3,
and presented our goal-statements to each other, and gave our impressions of
each others' goals.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I didn't really have a goal, but the exercise seemed to help, anyway.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also, I think it is making me nervous to treat Hacker School as
super-important.  It is important to make the best use of every hour, every
minute here, but at the same time, I shouldn't be constantly worrying about
whether or not, whatever I'm doing is the best use of my time here.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think I would like to form some good habits, and make a few good friends,
more than finish projects and build something uber-cool.  Of course, it would
be great to build awesome stuff (and may be the only reasonable way to form
habits, and make friends) but I shouldn't worry too much about time running
out. Never Graduate!
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>fft</category><category>goals</category><category>hackerschool</category><category>life</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/hacker-school-2014-06-25.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 13:51:07 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>