<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Noetic Nought (idea)</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/</link><description></description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 10:35:22 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Hacker School, 2014-06-11</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/hacker-school-2014-06-11.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-1" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sec-1"&gt;Plan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Continue with the Haskell tutorials, with additional reading from
Real World Haskell.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-2" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sec-2"&gt;Actual&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-2"&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finished exercises 4 and 5.
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learnt about Type classes in Haskell and how to create them and
make data types instances of them.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also came across a new algorithm of sieving called the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sieve_of_Sundaram"&gt;Sieve of
Sundaram&lt;/a&gt;, which was discovered by a student.  Surprisingly, I
never heard of it before!
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-3" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sec-3"&gt;Miscellaneous&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-3"&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A few of us had an interesting discussion about various places
people grew up in and visited, and the cultures, etc.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Idea: implement a GitHub dashboard for organizations (say, HS
batches) that give you different statistics, and interesting
graphs. (Use elm?) [Update: Tom is working on HS and GitHub
integration. So, that's perfect!]
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>github</category><category>hackerschool</category><category>haskell</category><category>idea</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/hacker-school-2014-06-11.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 19:02:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Scraping Google Groups</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/scraping-google-groups.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I was playing around with a few ideas for creating a timeline for the
mumbai ultimate group, and as a part of playing around with stuff, for
that idea, I ended up wanting to scrape all the emails on our google
group.  After looking around a little bit, I failed to find anything
that claims to be able to do this.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
So I ended up writing my own &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/punchagan/7947337"&gt;hacky script&lt;/a&gt; to download all the emails
sent on the group.  Like I said, this is a hack and can be improved
quite a bit, but I am not inclined to do anything about it, right
now.  Since, everything about google groups is ajaxy, this script uses
selenium and does things on the page, that one would do by hand.  It's
not something that I am proud of, but it does the job!
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>email</category><category>hack</category><category>idea</category><category>mumbai</category><category>ultimate</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/scraping-google-groups.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:55:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Pair Blogging</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/pair-blogging.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I like the idea of pair blogging. Cate and Sacha, seem to be doing
it (intentionally or not). One person blogs on a topic he/she's
presently thinking about and the other person posts his/her views
on the same issue.  Well, comments are meant for that, but a blog
post seems to give you greater freedom.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
PS: I called it pair-blogging. I don't know if it already has a
name or if pair-blogging means something else.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>idea</category><category>note</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/pair-blogging.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2010 04:05:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Change &amp; Free flow</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/change-free-flow.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
No.  Not the Obama change.  I'm talking of change as in small
denominations of cash.  Everybody is reluctant to part with
it.  There's always a problem with getting it.  I'm often worried
before getting into a bus or an auto, or going to a shop whether
or not the guy would give me change for a 50, 100 or a 500.
People so reluctant to "part" with it. What are they saving it
for?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I think the situation would be much better if people readily gave
it, when required.  There would be a free flow and if not anything
more, I wouldn't have to worry about it when going somewhere.
But, I "feel" this would actually reduce the instances when both
the parties don't have enough change with them. What do you think?
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>idea</category><category>money</category><category>note</category><category>people</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/change-free-flow.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2010 10:33:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Competition and Population</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/competition-and-population.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I've often got bad service from "service providers" - hotels,
restaurants, phone services, Internet services etc. I guess that's
due to the population in India. If one customer goes back unhappy
that doesn't really make a difference, because there would be
hundred others already waiting in the queue.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
You, as a, service provider would get your share of customers and
profits, no matter how bad you are. Thanks to the population.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
One solution could be, to write about the bad service you got from
a provider and make people aware of it, but often there aren't
enough options, for others to choose from. Inevitably, the bad
service provider is going to get some customers. What's the way
out?
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>idea</category><category>note</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/competition-and-population.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2010 10:25:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>