<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Noetic Nought (linux)</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/</link><description></description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 10:35:22 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Let there be light, in skype!</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/let-there-be-light-in-skype.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
At home, my video would always show a silhouette in G+ and Skype, and
I always thought that this was because the lighting at home was not
sufficient.  At office, the video was decent.  But, moving to sit
right under the light also didn't help much.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Struggling with a bunch of tools like &lt;code&gt;v4lctl&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;guvcview&lt;/code&gt; didn't
help. But, during these struggles I noticed that &lt;code&gt;cheese&lt;/code&gt; would show
me bright and cheerful, while all the other programs showed my
silhouette.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I set out to "fake" the output of &lt;code&gt;cheese&lt;/code&gt; as a video device that
skype and other programs could use. But, I didn't have to go all the
way.  I ended up using &lt;a href="https://github.com/umlaeute/v4l2loopback/"&gt;v4l2loopback&lt;/a&gt; to create a loopback video device,
and just using &lt;code&gt;gst-launch&lt;/code&gt; to redirect video to that device, did the
trick!  Thanks gstreamer!  Thanks v4l2loopback! :)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Here's a convenient &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/punchagan/9859210"&gt;script&lt;/a&gt; to use it every time I need it.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src="https://gist.github.com/9859210.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</description><category>hack</category><category>linux</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/let-there-be-light-in-skype.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2014 17:52:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>numpy, pacman and me</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/numpy-pacman-and-me.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I'm now officially a part of the Arch Linux community! Arch Linux
is a lightweight and flexible Linux® distribution that tries to
Keep It Simple.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I have started using arch from less than a week or so. It took me
a while, not too long, to realize the beauty of this distro. I was
trying to tweak the settings of my org-mode's remember (on
Karmic), trying to make it work the way I liked it. After breaking
my head with .emacs and lisp for a while, I realized the version
of my org-mode was way different from the version of the docs, I
was reading. It didn't take long to figure out, which version of
org-mode to get. As a matter of curiosity, I checked AUR for the
version, and true to Arch's reputation it was bleeding edge! I was
still using Karmic, since I hadn't got my Arch installation
working the way I like it, yet. Out of laziness. sudo reboot; to
hell with laziness!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I was setting up things I regularly use, tweaking my way
around. After a day or so, I find python-numpy is out of date. And
to top it, an orphaned package! I didn't feel one bit good about
this. After some futile attempts to suppress my discomfort, I sat
down to work.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
After an afternoon of effort, I created my first PKGBUILD. :) I
now have python-numpy installed using pacman! Pleasure to join the
Arch User Community! Also, thanks to lifeeth and Lynus Vaz, for
the sparks.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
PS: I'm using Arch with Openbox. It's neat! PPS: org-mode is
really awesome! It's a world in itself. life in plain text,
truly!]
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>linux</category><category>numpy</category><category>ology</category><category>orgmode</category><category>python</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/numpy-pacman-and-me.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2010 06:14:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>