<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Noetic Nought (python)</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/</link><description></description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 10:27:04 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Hacker School, 2014-08-19</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/hacker-school-2014-08-19.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I spent most of the day working through David Beazly's tutorials on
generators and coroutines, and it was mind bending.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I learnt about &lt;code&gt;send&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;throw&lt;/code&gt; methods on generators!  I hadn't heard of
them before, and was totally surprised to come across them.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I spent a little time late in the day getting class diffs working, and
refactoring the api-diff tool to remove duplication of code between classes
and modules. But, not very happy with the way I did it.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>hackerschool</category><category>python</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/hacker-school-2014-08-19.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2014 22:06:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hacker School, 2014-08-18</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/hacker-school-2014-08-18.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I refactored the API-diff code, and am pretty happy with what I have right
now, and need to add support for diffing Classes. I'm considering using
&lt;a href="http://www.astroid.org"&gt;Atstroid&lt;/a&gt; instead of Python's &lt;code&gt;ast&lt;/code&gt; module, since some of the work that I want
to do, has already been done for me.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With the white-boarding group, we worked on a set of simple exercises for
strings and arrays.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;José Valim's presentation on Elixir was interesting and got me reading up a
stuff about concurrency, and related stuff.  Thanks!
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>elixir</category><category>hackerschool</category><category>python</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/hacker-school-2014-08-18.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 17:11:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hacker School, 2014-08-17</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/hacker-school-2014-08-17.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-1" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sec-1"&gt;Friday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-1"&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated my HS profile page with projects that I worked on, and a short bio.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Joined the group discussing algorithmic complexity
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Submitted a pull request to blaggregator to fix issues with broken profile
images.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-2" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sec-2"&gt;Saturday &amp;amp; Sunday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I almost didn't write any code during the weekend.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>hackerschool</category><category>python</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/hacker-school-2014-08-17.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 01:59:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hacker School, 2014-08-14</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/hacker-school-2014-08-14.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I spent the morning cleaning up the "repr" functions of the diff classes, so
that the diff of functions between two modules can be printed out in a
somewhat meaningful way.
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I spent most of the afternoon, preparing to make a small presentation on how
&lt;code&gt;sys.path&lt;/code&gt; works in Python.  I thought I didn't do as good a job of it, as I
would've liked, but Tom thought it was not too bad…
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Looks like another of those days, where I didn't get much done…  I spent
the evening finishing off &lt;a href="http://craphound.com/homeland/"&gt;Homeland&lt;/a&gt;. It's a brilliant book, and everyone who
cares about the Government and policies and technology MUST read it!  Thanks
Cory.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>hackerschool</category><category>python</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/hacker-school-2014-08-14.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 22:09:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hacker School, 2014-08-13</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/hacker-school-2014-08-13.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I feel like I didn't get much done yesterday.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I mostly worked on the API differ, but didn't get much done.  I have a few
tests, and some code for diffing two functions, but I'm not very happy with
it.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I helped Giorgio and Carlos with using my client only &lt;code&gt;hs_oauth&lt;/code&gt;
script/library, for their Zulip bot.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The white boarding group worked on some binary related problems, and it was
fun.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I looked at how the HS OAuth backend works on blaggregator and thought about
how to go about fixing the issue of broken images on the site.  The problem
happens because the image URLs are returned from the HS API calls, that are
made whenever a user logs in(?), and the URLs are cached.  Since, HS uses
cloudfront for its assets, the URLs expire after a period of time, and the
cached urls in blag's database need to be updated.  There could be two ways
of doing it -
&lt;ol class="org-ol"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check if the URL 404s, every time a URL is requested, on the server side.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do it on the client side, with some javascript magic.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Intuitively, I feel like 2. would be better, but Madhu suggested
that 1. wouldn't be that bad either.  We could try both out, and see which
works better I suppose.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I'd be interested to try this out, sometime.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>hackerschool</category><category>python</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/hacker-school-2014-08-13.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 15:11:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hacker School, 2014-08-12</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/hacker-school-2014-08-12.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An issue I was seeing with &lt;code&gt;pip&lt;/code&gt; and a package installed in
&lt;code&gt;system-site-packages&lt;/code&gt; turned out to be non-reproducible.  It was probably
PEBKAC.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was wondering around in the morning trying to find something to work on.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I decided to work on Pankaj's idea to write a tool that gives you API
differences between two versions of a library.  It would be useful to have
the list of public API changes in a library you use, to estimate the cost of
updating to the newer version, without having to manually go through all the
changes.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I spent some time talking to Sophia, and looking at her FTP server's
refactored code.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>hackerschool</category><category>python</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/hacker-school-2014-08-12.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2014 14:30:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hacker School, 2014-08-11</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/hacker-school-2014-08-11.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I spent about an hour in the morning testing out the staging blaggregator
instance, and things seemed to work as expected.  Side note, I got added as a
collaborator on the blaggregator repo!
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We worked through the first chapter on getting video working, but we mostly
ended up just copying code rather than actually understanding/carefully
studying it.  I'm not sure how I feel about it, but we got to display fancy
stuff.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wasn't feeling like working on any of my 'old'/'ongoing' projects, and
since Mondays don't feel very productive, I worked on writing a couple of
simple scripts to create twitter lists of HSers, batch wise.

&lt;p&gt;
For the HS API, I just reused some old code I had lying around from my
experiments with the OAuth2 API, though I had to tweak it a little bit to be
able to actually login, using requests. Something about CSRF tokens seems to
have changed.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In the process, I found that twitter's API isn't very pleasant to use.  Or
may be it's the fact that I was using python twitter client without getting
my own client id/key, but the whole experience of dealing with the twitter
API wasn't a pleasant one at all!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amber, Daria and I also spent about an hour white-boarding some problems from
the Cracking the Code Interview book.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I ended up fixing some minor issues with blaggregator and am hoping that the
long pending PR will be merged today.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>django</category><category>hackerschool</category><category>python</category><category>twitter</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/hacker-school-2014-08-11.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2014 15:16:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hacker School, 2014-08-08</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/hacker-school-2014-08-08.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I spent the morning doing some white-boarding interview practice with a Jorge
and Brian.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I spent the rest of the day, playing with PyPy and working through &lt;a href="http://morepypy.blogspot.in/2011/04/tutorial-writing-interpreter-with-pypy.html"&gt;a tutorial&lt;/a&gt;
that teaches us to write a BF interpreter.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I spent the Saturday revamping my Emacs config.  The main issue with my
config was having a "package" list, of all the packages that the
configuration uses, in case we are trying to duplicate it elsewhere.  I
noticed that this gets out of sync, because I install packages by hand and
never update this list.  I wrote up &lt;a href="https://github.com/punchagan/dot-emacs/blob/master/user-lisp/setup-defuns.el"&gt;some code&lt;/a&gt;, that keeps this list in sync
with all the packages I have installed.  I configured el-get to play well
with my config, and am pretty happy with my setup, though I still have to add
some matching/searching features with helm/ido/whatever else.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I spent the Sunday writing a patch to &lt;a href="https://github.com/punchagan/xtab/tree/kill-by-memory"&gt;xtab&lt;/a&gt; to be able to limit the number of
tabs in Chromium by the memory it uses.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>chrome</category><category>emacs</category><category>hackerschool</category><category>python</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/hacker-school-2014-08-08.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 00:56:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hacker School, 2014-08-03</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/hacker-school-2014-08-03.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-1" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sec-1"&gt;Friday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-1"&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On Friday, I didn't do the exercises that everyone else doing job prep were
doing.  I wanted to continue writing C code, and continued to work on the
&lt;code&gt;bencode&lt;/code&gt; parser in C.  I barely was able to finish adding support for lists.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I got comfortable using Valgrind, in the process of debugging a stupidity of
not using &lt;code&gt;realloc&lt;/code&gt; correctly.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What I was able to write with Python in an hour or so, I have been writing
for about a day, in C, and haven't yet finished it!  It definitely doesn't
help that my C is very rusty…
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-2" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sec-2"&gt;Saturday &amp;amp; Sunday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-2"&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I didn't work much, and went around New York with Madhu.  We went to quite
a few places around here, the highlight being, the view of Manhattan's
skyline from the Staten Island Ferry.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NYC's library also had an interesting exhibhition on the history of
America, just before and during WW-I.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On Sunday, I tried out Mary TTS on the raspberry pi, and it is simply
unusable.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I then, started writing a simple wrapper around Google's tts that is used
by Google translate.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The TTS part is more or less working right now, the next step would be to
deploy it on the RaspberryPi and start using it as a radio, to see what my
needs are like. Hooking it up to &lt;a href="https://github.com/jasperproject/jasper-client"&gt;Jasper client&lt;/a&gt; seems like a good idea,
right now… though I'm not sure if it would work very well, with the pi's
audio output drowning out the voice commands.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>C</category><category>hackerschool</category><category>python</category><category>raspberry-pi</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/hacker-school-2014-08-03.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2014 20:10:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hacker School, 2014-07-28</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/hacker-school-2014-07-28.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There seemed to be excitement in the space to have Jessica around.  We had
coffee with her, and I chatted with her briefly. She encouraged me to try and
send a patch to CPython, that involved debugging and fixing some C issues.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I spent some time with Tom, while he tried to get &lt;code&gt;cinspect&lt;/code&gt; working for him,
and it seemed like having the developer next to you, helped.  As always.  We
didn't make any fixes to the code, but it worked.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I spent the afternoon, adding tests for a simple issue, to see how patches are sent.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Later, I paired with Sophia for an hour to refactor the vcs code. It's
beginning to look much better than what it used to, and I like that.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jessica's talk on buffer overflows was enlightening and entertaining. It was
very similar to a talk that Max gave on one of the thursdays, but it was
exciting nevertheless.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After the talk, I am inspired to try and work through the Hacking: Art of
exploitation, at some point. I'm beginning to feel like time at HackerSchool
running out!
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>C</category><category>hackerschool</category><category>python</category><category>version_control</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/hacker-school-2014-07-28.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2014 02:23:39 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>