<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Noetic Nought (quotes)</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/tags/quotes.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 03:32:41 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Quotes [2014-11-01]</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/quotes-2014-11-01.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wanted to change the world. But I have found that the only thing
one can be sure of changing is oneself. ~ Aldous Huxley
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The true voyage of discovery consists not of going to new places,
but of having a new pair of eyes. — Marcel Proust (1871–1922)
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;All that is necessary for evil to triumph is for good men to do nothing. — Edmund Burke
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"I think that it's extraordinarily important that we in computer science keep
  fun in computing. When it started out, it was an awful lot of fun. Of course,
the paying customers got shafted every now and then, and after a while we
began to take their complaints seriously. We began to feel as if we really
were responsible for the successful, error-free perfect use of these
machines. I don't think we are. I think we're responsible for stretching
them, setting them off in new directions, and keeping fun in the house. I
hope the field of computer science never loses its sense of fun. Above all, I
hope we don't become missionaries. Don't feel as if you're Bible
salesmen. The world has too many of those already. What you know about
computing other people will learn. Don't feel as if the key to successful
computing is only in your hands. What's in your hands, I think and hope, is
intelligence: the ability to see the machine as more than when you were first
led up to it, that you can make it more." – &lt;i&gt;Alan J. Perlis (April 1,
1922-February 7, 1990)&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Forgetting is like radiation: you cannot smell it, you cannot taste it, and
  when you finally notice the damage, it is already irreversible – &lt;i&gt;Piotr
Wozniack&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;"Computer Science is no more about computers than astronomy is about telescopes" – &lt;i&gt;Edsger Dijkstra&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>quotes</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/quotes-2014-11-01.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2014 20:16:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Quotes [2014-04-04]</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/quotes-2014-04-04.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“My idea of dominating is that I get all of the players on my team
to play better than if I wasn’t there.” – Ben Wiggins
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;“It is a risk to love. What if it doesn't work out? Ah, but what if
it does.”  ― Peter McWilliams
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;"Wherever you go, go with all your heart" – &lt;i&gt;Confucius&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Work is never finished, only abandoned.” —Paul Valéry
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Satisfaction of one's curiosity is one of the greatest sources of happiness in life." – Linus Pauling
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>quotes</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/quotes-2014-04-04.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2014 18:30:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Quotes [2014-01-31]</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/quotes-2014-01-31.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Silence is the language of god. All else is poor translation." ~Rumi
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“To love at all is to be vulnerable. Love anything, and your heart
  will certainly be wrung and possibly be broken. If you want to make
sure of keeping it intact, you must give your heart to no one, not
even to an animal. Wrap it carefully round with hobbies and little
luxuries; avoid all entanglements; lock it up safe in the casket or
coffin of your selfishness. But in that casket — safe, dark,
motionless, airless — it will change. It will not be broken; it will
become unbreakable, impenetrable, irredeemable. The alternative to
tragedy, or at least to the risk of tragedy, is damnation. The only
place outside of Heaven where you can be perfectly safe from all the
dangers and perturbations of love is Hell.” – &lt;i&gt;C. S. Lewis&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Quality is the result of a million selfless acts of care – not just
  of any great method that descends from the heavens. That these acts
are simple doesn't mean that they are simplistic; and it hardly
means that they are easy. They are nonetheless the fabric of
greatness and, more so, of beauty in any human endeavor. To ignore
them is not yet to be fully human.  – James O. Coplien, &lt;i&gt;Foreword
to Clean Code&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;“We are all in the same boat, in a stormy sea, and we owe each other
a terrible loyalty.” – G.K. Chesterton
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The road to wisdom? – Well, it's plain and simple to express:

&lt;p&gt;
Err
and err
and err again
but less
and less
and less.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
– Piet Hein (Grooks)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>quotes</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/quotes-2014-01-31.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 12:40:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Quotes [2013-12-23]</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/quotes-2013-12-23.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Debugging is twice as hard as writing the code in the first
  place. Therefore, if you write the code as cleverly as possible, you
are, by definition, not smart enough to debug it." –Brian Kernighan
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;“Lighthouses don’t go running all over an island looking for boats
to save; they just stand there shining.” ― Anne Lamott
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Life is an awful, ugly place to not have a best friend. ― Sarah Dessen
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Warning: everything saved will be lost. — Wii notification
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Happiness is nothing more than good health and a bad memory.  – Albert Schweitzer
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>quotes</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/quotes-2013-12-23.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2013 08:52:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Quotes [2013-11-24]</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/quotes-2013-11-24.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Life is a tragedy when seen in close-up, but a comedy in a
long-shot. – &lt;i&gt;Charlie Chaplin&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Another flaw in the human character is that everyone wants to build
and nobody wants to do maintenance. – &lt;i&gt;Kurt Vonnegut&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;In three words I can sum up everything I’ve learned about life: it
goes on. – &lt;i&gt;Robert Frost&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Nothing of me is original. I am the combined efforts of everyone
I’ve every known. – &lt;i&gt;Chuck Palahniuk&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>quotes</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/quotes-2013-11-24.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2013 16:33:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Quotes [2013-11-21]</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/quotes-2013-11-21.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scientists study the world as it is; engineers create the world that
has never been. – &lt;i&gt;Theodore von Karman&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;If you can love someone with your whole heart, even one person, then
  there’s salvation in life. Even if you can’t get together with that
person. – &lt;i&gt;Haruki Murakami&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The truth is rarely pure and never simple – &lt;i&gt;Oscar Wilde&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Memories warm you up from the inside. But they also tear you apart.
― &lt;i&gt;Haruki Murakami&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;We are what we repeatedly do. Excellence, then, is not an act, but a
habit. – &lt;i&gt;Aristotle&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>quotes</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/quotes-2013-11-21.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 16:07:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Quotes [2013-10-28]</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/quotes-2013-10-28.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The enjoyment of one's tools is an essential ingredient of
successful work. – &lt;i&gt;Donald E. Knuth&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Respect yourself enough to walk away from anything that no longer
serves you, grows you, or makes you happy. — &lt;i&gt;Robert Tew&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;It is not in the stars to hold our destiny but in ourselves.
&lt;i&gt;William Shakespeare&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I saw that my life was a vast glowing empty page and I could do
anything I wanted. – &lt;i&gt;Jack Kerouac&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The truth is, everyone is going to hurt you. You just got to find
the ones worth suffering for. – &lt;i&gt;Bob Marley&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>quotes</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/quotes-2013-10-28.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2013 13:34:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Quotes [2013-10-19]</title><link>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/quotes-2013-10-19.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Somewhere in the world someone is training when you are not. When
you race him, he will win. – &lt;i&gt;Tom Fleming&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Because when something happens, she’s the person I want to tell. The
most basic indicator of love. – &lt;i&gt;David Levithan&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;If you are not embarrassed by the first version of your product,
you've launched too late. – &lt;i&gt;Reid Hoffman&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;“Nothing of me is original. I am the combined effort of everyone
I've ever known.” ― &lt;i&gt;Chuck Palahniuk&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;"I fell in love with the way you sleep; slowly then all at once"
&lt;i&gt;John Green&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>quotes</category><guid>http://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/quotes-2013-10-19.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2013 14:35:52 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>