<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Noetic Nought (time)</title><link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/tags/time.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 17:56:05 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Assist time</title><link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/assist-time.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I sometimes hang out on &lt;a href="http://webchat.freenode.net/?channels=%2523org-mode"&gt;#org-mode&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://webchat.freenode.net/?channels=%2523nikola"&gt;#nikola&lt;/a&gt; and answer questions. I usually am
not able to answer off the top of my head and I look up docs or dig through the
code.  Sometimes, we find ready-made documented answers, but other times we end
up contributing some documentation, filing an issue, submitting a patch or
hacking up something for that super-special use-case.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Until now, I looked at this time as IRC time, which loosely translates to
distraction time.  But, I'm usually learning about the tools I use a little bit
more. Even when I'm not, I'm helping someone do something they want to do.
Sometimes empowering them to fix future problems on their own.  And indirectly
making the user community a wee-bit happier, and possibly the software a tiny
bit better.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This isn't limited just to helping someone on IRC.  Helping out a co-worker do
something that they are new to, or just adding a comment or editing a
Stack-overflow answer may end up in the "distraction time" bin, just because
you weren't doing something on your TODO list.  It needn't be.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Taking cue from &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Assist_(football)"&gt;scorers in Football&lt;/a&gt;, I decided to call this time &lt;b&gt;assist time&lt;/b&gt;
and to try to start seeing this time as (semi-)productive. Naming helps.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>blab</category><category>blag</category><category>productivity</category><category>programming</category><category>time</category><guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/assist-time.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 14:28:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Asking vs. Figuring out</title><link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/asking-vs-figuring-out.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Should one take the easy route of asking someone who knows, if she
is sitting right next to you? Or should we try and find out first,
before asking her? Should one value his time more than others' or
others' time more than his own?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Would we learn more if we tried to find out ourselves? Does
learning more, make sense? Is it worth spending the extra time?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I'm just talking of simple things that you could figure out by
spending a couple of minutes of searching the web or 5 minutes of
thinking or 10 minutes of reading a book.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>note</category><category>thought</category><category>time</category><guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/asking-vs-figuring-out.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2010 15:43:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>