<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Noetic Nought (workflow)</title><link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/tags/workflow.xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 May 2016 11:35:02 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Tedium in work-flows</title><link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/tedium-in-work-flows.html</link><dc:creator>punchagan</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I use &lt;a href="http://getnikola.com"&gt;Nikola&lt;/a&gt; for generating this blog. When creating a new post, it prompts for
a title, and creates a file for the post.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Often I'm starting off with only a vague idea that needs to be fleshed out
before it can be published (or discarded). It is quite difficult to come up
with a title at this stage. I just want to start a draft and write things down!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I could use a "draft-title" and change it after finishing a post, but this
feels tedious – requires 3 steps – change the title, post filename and post
slug.  The last two steps are optional, really, but I feel they are important
especially when the original title is very different from the new one.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Being forced to come up with a title before anything else, feels tedious and,
adds to the effort required to start off a new post.  I shouldn't really be
worrying about the effort required to change the title of an unwritten post,
but it happens subconsciously.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
To work around this, I now have a "re-title utility" in my editor that takes
care of all the tedious details.  I can start with a random title, like
Draft-1, and change it when I'm done with the post.  I feel this is going to
lead to a lot more drafts, at the very least, if not published posts.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Another work-flow related thing I came across recently was @Malabarba's &lt;a href="https://github.com/clojure-emacs/cider/issues/1717#issue-150907043"&gt;issue&lt;/a&gt;
on CIDER (an IDE for Clojure in Emacs).  The &lt;a href="http://www.braveclojure.com/getting-started/#Using_the_REPL"&gt;REPL&lt;/a&gt; takes a while to startup and
this caused him to not use CIDER for running tests, if there wasn't an already
open REPL.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The tedium that people feel effects how they use the tool.  Not surprisingly,
making tedious-feeling tasks a breeze with the tool also effects how and how
much they use it.  Subtle variations in a work-flow could make or break it.
How do you discover such potential work-flow make-or-break-ers? I think, these
things would help:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the tool yourself (dog-food)
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talk to (or watch!) people using your tool
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look at work-flows in other similar tools
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thinking explicitly about various scenarios and simplifying or improving
work-flows
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I'd love to hear examples of this, and any ideas or thoughts you may have on
identifying and fixing such things!
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>blab</category><category>programming</category><category>user-experience</category><category>workflow</category><guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/posts/tedium-in-work-flows.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2016 11:13:37 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>